University of Connecticut 1998.0236
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
University of Connecticut, Admissions Office Records
1955-2003.
1998.0236
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
1.5 Linear feet
Administrative records of the University of Connecticut Admissions office. The collections consists primarily of enrollment reports, although several other reports and some brochures are also included.
University of Connecticut. Admissions Office.
History
The University of Connecticut traces its founding to the establishment of the Storrs Agricultural School on 21 April 1881 by an act of the Connecticut General Assembly. The main campus, located in Storrs, Connecticut was originally a gift of 170 acres of land, several frame buildings, and money from Charles and Augustus Storrs. The School opened on 28 September 1881, with twelve students in the first class. Before the turn of the century there were two name changes ( Storrs Agricultural College 1893, Connecticut Agricultural College 1899). In 1933, two years after the institution celebrated its fiftieth anniversary, it became Connecticut State College, a name more in keeping with its steady advances and broadened mission. Six years later, in 1939, the General Assembly designated the institution the University of Connecticut, an acknowledgment of the institution's developing importance to the State in graduate and professional education, research and public service.
It is the function of the Admissions Office to enrol qualified new students at the University. To support this goal, the office works with interested students and guidance counselors through Open Houses, as well as participating in regional and national college fairs.
As of Fall 2003, the University of Connecticut enrolled 19,287 undergraduates and 7,342 graduate and professional students in seventeen Schools and Colleges. Admissions at the University is now divided between two offices, Undergraduate Admissions and the Graduate School. Enrollment statistics are collected, maintained and reported by the Office of Institutional Research (OIR).
Scope and Content
The collection consists primarily of enrollment reports. Recent announcements, brochures, and several related reports have been included.
Arrangement
Series I: Administrative Records ( 1955-2003 ) includes all the files acquired from, or information supplied by, the Admissions Office.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University's history. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Admissions Newsletter
Report on Admissions, 1961-1980
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
These materials are distributed periodically throughout the administration of the University. The most recent collection of enrollment statistics is available electronically from the Office of Institutional Research.
University of Connecticut.; Administrative Records.; Brochures.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Newsletters.; Photocopies.; Publications.; Storrs, Conn.
- Series I: Administrative Records, 1955-2003
  - Announcements, 2003 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Annual report, 1966-1981 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Annual report--preliminary, 1967-1983 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Brochures, undated (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Class profile, 1980 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Class profile, 1985 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Enrollment reports
    - 1955 October - 1956 Spring (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - 1957 October - 1958 Spring (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - 1958 September - 1959 February (Box 1:, Folder 9)
    - 1964 February - October (Box 1:, Folder 10)
    - 1965-1969 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
    - 1967 January - October (Box 1:, Folder 12)
    - 1968 January - September (Box 1:, Folder 13)
    - 1969-1972 (Box 1:, Folder 14-15)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - 1975-1977 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - 1978-1980 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
    - 1980-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
    - 1981-1983 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
    - 1988 (Box 1:, Folder 24)
    - 1991-1993 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
    - 1994-1996 (Box 1:, Folder 26)
  - High School Graduate report, 1976-1983 (Box 2:, Folder 27)
  - Marketing plan, 1989 (Box 2:, Folder 28)
  - Student questionnaire results, 1991 (Box 2:, Folder 30)